Guide to the Mary Beth Edelson Papers MSS.549
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Professional Activities, 1950-2016 (inclusive); 1970-2016 (bulk); 53.99 Linear Feet in 100 manuscript boxes, 10 flat boxes, 11 oversized flat boxes, and 6 oversized folders
  - Sub-Series I.B: Exhibitions and Performances, 1967-2016 (inclusive); 1970-2016 (bulk); 14.27 Linear Feet in 23 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 6 oversized flat boxes, and 2 oversized folders
    - Boston, 1985-1997 (Box 16, Folder 4-8, Box 97, Folder 2-3)
      Materials in these folders pertain to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions and performances in Boston and the surrounding area. Locations include the McMullen Museum, the Photo Resources Center, and Danforth.
    - California, 1975-1979, 1996-1998, 2015-2016 (Box 16, Folder 9-11, Box 97, Folder 4-5)
      Materials in these folders relate to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the One Archive Foundation (Los Angeles) and the Rena Bransten Gallery (San Francisco). There are also slides relating to a performance in Chico.
    - Canada, 1983-2011 (Box 17, Folder 9-11, Box 97, Folder 6-10, Box 98, Folder 1-4)
      Materials in these folders relate to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the Banff for Centre of Arts (Banff), Mendel Art Gallery (Saskatoon), University of Toronto, Walter Phillips Gallery (Banff), London Gallery (Quebec City), and the Yukon Arts Centre (Whitehorse).
    - Chiffons, 1990-2000 (Box 17, Folder 6, Box 98, Folder 5-8, Box 99, Folder 1-2)
    - Conneticut - Aldrich Contemporary Art Museum, 2013-2014 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
    - Denmark - Copenhagen, 1996-2000, 2012 (Box 17, Folder 9-12, Box 111, Folder 2, Flat-file-folder 3 Right)
      These folders contain materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibition at the Galleri Nicolai Wallner, as well as materials related to workshops she facilited in Copenhagen.
    - "Edelson New York City 9/11/01" Poster, 2001 (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - France, 1993, 2014-2016 (Box 18, Folder 1-3, Box 111, Folder 8)
      These folders contain materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the FRAC Lorraine Collection (Metz), Centre Pompidou (Metz), and in Grenoble.
    - Austria and Switzerland, 1998, 2001-2006 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Germany, 1997-2015 (Box 18, Folder 4-11, Box 99, Folder 3-4, Box 110, Folder 29)
      These folders contain materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions in Berlin, Bremen (Paula Modersohn-Becker Museum), and Hamberg (Diana Krause Gallery).
    - Illinois - Chicago, 1976-1982, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 1, Box 99, Folder 5)
      These folders contain materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the Dobrick Gallery and N.A.M.E. Gallery.
    - Independent New York Art Fair, 2012 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Indiana, 1967-1992 (Box 19, Folder 3-10, Box 99, Folder 6-8, Box 100, Folder 1)
      These folders contain materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the Fort Wayne Museum of Art (Fort Wayne), Herron Gallery (Indianapolis), St. Mary's College (Notre Dame), Talbot Gallery (Indianapolis), and Indiana State University (Terre Haute).
    - Installation - Collective Workshop, Atlanta, GA (Slides), 1979 (Box 100, Folder 2-3)
    - Installation - Edelson's Art (Washington, D.C., New Orleans, Chicago) (Slides), 1973-2004 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Installation - Firsthand, Anti-Essentialist Feeding Frenzy (Slides), circa 1990s (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Installation - Gandhi Rocks, Flying Rocks (Slides), circa 1970s-1980s (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Iowa, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 11-12, Box 100, Folder 7-8)
    - JFK-SF Workshop, Wall Painting, Performance (Slides), undated (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Lemon Concentrate, Ewing Gallery, University of Tennessee (Slides), 1989 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - L'Heure Des Sorcieres (Quimper, France), 2013-2014 (Box 19, Folder 13-14, Box 120, Folder 4)
    - Making Eye Contact, 2004, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 15, Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Minnesota - Walker Art Center, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Netherlands, 1978-1980, 2006, 2012-2013 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
      Materials in these folders pertain to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions in Amsterdam and Arnhem.
    - New Jersey - Bernstein Gallery (Woodrow Wilson School of Public Policy, Princeton University), 2015 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - New Orleans, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 5-6, Box 100, Folder 11)
    - New York City - Galleries, 1971-2016 (Box 20, Folder 7-13, Box 21, Folder 1-8, Box 100, Folder 12-13)
      Materials in these folders pertain to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the following galleries: Accola Griefen Gallery (Collaborative), BACA Downtown, D.C. Moore Gallery, Elise Meyer Gallery, Fawbush Gallery, Fine Arts Building, Galerie Lelong, Garth Green Gallery, P.P.O.W. Gallery, Keneleba House Gallery, Max Hutchinson Gallery, Nicole Klagsburn Gallery, Lombard/Fried Fine Arts, and Steinbaum Krauss Gallery.
    - New York City - Group Exhibits, 1975-2008 (Box 21, Folder 9, Box 120, Folder 6, Flat-file-folder 3)
    - New York City - Museums, 1976-2015 (Box 21, Folder 10-16, 18, Box 101, Folder 1-2)
      Materials in these folders pertain to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the following museums: Brooklyn Museum, Chelsea Museum, Museum of Modern Art (MoMA), New Museum, MoMA PS.1 (Project Studios One), Queens Museum, and Whitney Museum.
    - New York City - Exhibition at St. Regis Hotel and De Beers Jewellery, 2011 (Box 21, Folder 17, Box 115, Folder 8)
    - New York State, 1979-2006 (Box 22, Folder 1-11, Box 101, Folder 3-7)
      Materials in these folders pertain to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the following museums and galleries: Bard College Center for Curatorial Studies (Annandale-on-Hudson), Guild Hall (East Hampton), Hallwalls Contemporary Arts Center (Buffalo), Hillwood Art Gallery at C.W. Post Campus (Brookville), Katonah Museum of Art (Katonah), Neuberger Museum of Art (Purchase), Albright-Knox Art Gallery (Buffalo), and Stony Brook Univeristy (Stony Brook).
    - Norway, 2003-2005 (Box 22, Folder 13, Box 101, Folder 8)
    - Ohio, 1981-1982, 1990-1993 (Box 22, Folder 14, Box 23, Folder 1-2, Box 101, Folder 9-14)
      These folders contains materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions and performances at the following locations: Wright State University (Dayton), Cincinnati, Cleveland, Athens, and Kenyon College (Gambier).
    - Pennsylvania - Andy Warhol Museum, 2009 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Performances, 1970-2013 (Box 23, Folder 4-7, Box 101, Folder 15, Box 102, Folder 1-4)
      These folders contains materials related to Mary Beth Edelson's art performances, including Creation Begins with a Green Light and Shopping for a New Mate, as well as photographs of performances at Amherst, Massachusetts and Oxbow, Michigan.
    - Performances, 1970-2013 (Box 110, Folder 7, Box 114, Folder 8, Box 116, Folder 12)
    - Photographic Performances (Slides), 1973-1992 (Box 102, Folder 5-10, Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Portrait Project, 2004-2006 (Box 23, Folder 8-11, Box 24, Folder 1-2, Box 110, Folder 13, Box 114, Folder 9, Box 115, Folder 7)
    - Public Performances, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Re-Scripting the Story: Mary Beth Edelson, 1970-2000 (Traveling Exhibition), 1985-2001 (Box 24, Folder 4-6, Box 114, Folder 15)
    - Sexual Fantasies, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 7, Box 114, Folder 19, Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Shapeshifters (Traveling Exhibition), 1981-1992 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Spain, 2006-2007 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Story Gathering Boxes, 1978-2014 (Box 25, Folder 2-6)
    - Sweden -- Malmo Museum, 1998-2006 (Box 26, Folder 1-7, Box 103, Folder 2)
    - Switzerland -- Verein Shedhalle Art Museum (Zurich), 2003 (Box 26, Folder 8, Box 103, Folder 3)
    - Texas, 2000-2001, 2009-2010 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Traveling Exhibitions -- Domestic, 1996, 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 3-10)
      Materials in these folders relate to Mary Beth Edelson's traveling exhibitions in the following states: California, Maryland, Texas, Pennsylvania, Tennessee, New York, Indiana, Ohio, and Illinois.
    - Trickster, 1981-1988 (Box 27, Folder 11-12, Box 28, Folder 1-3, Box 103, Folder 4)
    - United Kingdom, 1995-2014 (Box 28, Folder 4-8, Box 103, Folder 5-6)
      Materials in these folders relate to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the following galleries and museums: The Agency Gallery (London), John Hansard Gallery (University of Southhampton), and the Tate Modern (London).
    - Utopiana, 2006-2007 (Box 28, Folder 9, Box 115)
    - Vienna - Verbund Collection, 2014-2015 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - WACK! - Art of the Feminist Revolution, 2006-2009 (Box 29, Folder 1-2, Box 115, Folder 11-13, Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Washington, D.C., 1970-2013 (Box 29, Folder 3-10, Box 103, Folder 7-11, Box 110, Folder 9-10, Box 115, Folder 14, Box 120, Folder 1)
      These folders contain materials pertaining to Mary Beth Edelson's exhibitions at the following galleries: the Art Barn and Terminal Collaborative Group, American University, Corcoran Gallery of Art, John Troyer Fitzpatrick Gallery, and the W.R. Henri Gallery.
    - Washington, D.C. - "The Group" (Washington, D.C. Collaboration), 1970-1974 (Box 30, Folder 1, Box 115, Folder 14, Box 120)
    - Washington, D.C. - Washington Project for Arts, 1987-1989 (Box 30, Folder 2, Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Your 5,000 Years Are Up, 1987-1989 (Box 103, Folder 12-13)
  - Sub-Series I.C: Research Materials, 1959-2010 (inclusive); 1990-2006 (bulk); 6.78 Linear Feet in 13 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, 3 oversized flat boxes, and 1 oversized folder
    Sub-Series I.C contains written research materials and visual source materials that informed Mary Beth Edelson's artwork. In the 1990s, Edelson focused on Hollywood's portrayal of women and the femme fatale in film. To this effect, this sub-series contains her handwritten notes about various film noirs, as well as photographs of actresses including Marlene Dietrich, Judy Garland, Marilyn Monroe, Gloria Grahame, Sharon Stone, and Gena Rowlands. Sub-Series I.C also includes a range of visual source materials including images of flowers, goddesses, guns, people, and patterns – all of which served as sources of inspiration for Edelson's collage art.
    - Books (List of Research Materials), 1980, 1998, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Actresses, undated (Box 30, Folder 8-10, Box 31, Box 32, Folder 1-5)
      These folders contain photographs of the following actresses: Sigourney Weaver, Anjelica Huston, Barbara Stanwyck, Carmen Miranda, Gena Rowlands, Judy Garland, Mae West, Marilyn Monroe, Marlene Dietrich, Sharon Stone, and Tilda Swinton.
    - Animals, Dance and Music, New York and Statue of Liberty, 1993-1994, 2000-2004 (Box 32, Folder 6, Box 110, Folder 11)
    - Art, undated (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Bad Guys, 1973, 1987, 1994, 2006 (Box 32, Folder 8-9, Box 110, Folder 12)
    - Birth of Venus (Botticelli), undated (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Body Parts, undated (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Cave & Rocks, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Children, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Collage Art, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Difference/Race, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Exploitation Films, 1959-1969 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Film, Actors, and Promotional Shots, undated (Box 32, Folder 16, Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Film Lists, 1995-2000 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Flies and Fly Swatters, undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Flowers and Plants, 1972-2009 (Box 33, Folder 4-6, Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Gandhi, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Goddesses, undated (Box 34, Folder 3-5, Box 114, Folder 16)
    - Guns, undated (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Horror, undated (Box 34, Folder 7-8, Flat-file-folder 1 Right)
    - Landscapes, 1993-2005 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Men, 1975-2004 (Box 35, Folder 2-6, Box 114, Folder 17)
    - Movie Stars and Films Stills, undated (Box 35, Folder 7-8, Box 36, Folder 1-4)
    - Music and Dance, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Nelson Mandela, 1990-1994 (Box 36, Folder 6, Box 110, Folder 13)
    - New York and Statue of Liberty, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Nicole Brown Simpson, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Occult, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Patterns and Designs, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-2, Box 114, Folder 16)
    - People, undated (Box 37, Folder 3-7, Box 110, Folder 14)
    - Performance and Rituals - Source Materials, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Politics, 1975-2001 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Postcards, undated (Box 38, Folder 1-4)
    - Reference Posters and Other General Subjects, 2007-2009 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Religion, 2001-2002 (Box 38, Folder 6, Box 114, Folder 18, Box Shared Fales 086, Folder 15)
    - Research Materials & Notes - General, undated (Box 30, Folder 4-7)
    - Reverand Sun Myung Moon (Slides), undated (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook Items, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Shells, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Shooters/Women with Guns, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Soldiers, Skulls, and Skeletons, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Swords, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Table of Contents, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Things and Objects, undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Tunnels, undated (Box 39, Folder 6, Box 114, Folder 18)
    - Twin Peaks, 1990 (Box 104, Folder 2-3)
    - Utopia, 2004-2006 (Box 39, Folder 7, Box 110, Folder 16)
    - Violence, 1976-1991 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Waterfalls & Waves, undated (Box 39, Folder 9-10)
    - Women, 1970-2010 (Box 39, Folder 11-15, Box 40, Folder 1-6, Box 110, Folder 15-16)
    - Wonder Woman, undated (Box 40, Folder 7-8)
    - Writings - References, Background Materials, 1992-2001 (Box 40, Folder 9, Box 115, Folder 15)
    - Xeroxes of Photos, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
  - Sub-Series I.D: Teaching, Conferences, Workshops, and Affiliations, 1970-2015 (inclusive); 1973-2003 (bulk); 5.13 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes, 1 flat box, and 4 oversized flat boxes
    Sub-Series I.D focuses upon Mary Beth Edelson's role as arts educator and contains her syllabi, notes, lectures, slides, and some administrative papers related to her teaching appointments in Chicago, Michigan, Minneapolis, Pennsylvania, and Washington D.C.
    Edelson was also an active member of the feminist art community, which is reflected in this sub-series. In 1977, Edelson began an art collaboration with Suzanne Lacy (Los Angeles), Nil Yalter (Turkey), Ulrike Rosenbach (Germany), and Miriam Sharon (Israel), and in 2003, she self-published a book titled International Feminist Collaboration, 1977-1979 that contained copies of letters exchanged between the women and art project collaboration ideas. Drafts, Edelson's notes, and mock ups of the book can be found within this sub-series.
    In addition to Edelson's international feminist art collaboration, Sub-Series I.D contains papers related to the Heresies Collective, a feminist political arts group Edelson joined in the late 1970s. These materials include notes about the group and a few copies of their publication, Chrysalis. This sub-series also contains photographs, conference materials, and essays related to the Conference for Women in Visual Arts (CWVA), of which Edelson was a founder.
    Edelson was an advocate for female artists and the works they produced, and in the late 1980s and early 1990s, she was a member of the Title Nine Task Force. The group's mission was to increase the presence of women's art in museums, in accordance with the Title IX of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, which banned sex discrimination in federally funded organizations including the Guggenheim or Museum of Modern Art. Materials related to the Title Nine Task Force consist of posters and reports.
    This sub-series also contains posters advertising Edelson's speaking engagements, as well as some photographs of workshops and lectures.
    - Chicago - Teaching, 1999-2014 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Conference for Women in the Visual Arts (CWVA), 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 5-6, Box 110, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Poster - Enviromental Variations (Conference), 1983 (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Goddess Lecture (Slides), 1979 (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Great Lakes College Association (GLAC)/Assistants, 1986-2002 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Guerilla Girls - Women's Artists Terrorist Organizations, 1986-2003 (Box 41, Folder 8, Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Habits - International Feminist Collaborations, undated (Box 114, Folder 14)
    - Heresies, 1976-2008 (Box 42, Folder 1-5)
    - Heresies -- Chrysalis, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 6-7, Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Installations and Lecture Notes, 2002 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - International Feminist Collaboration, 1977-1979, 2003 (Box 42, Folder 9-12, Box 111, Folder 11-14, Box 116, Folder 5)
    - International Feminst Group, 1977-1979 (Box 43, Folder 1-3, Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Lectures, Panels, & Teaching Introductions, 1973-1999 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Minneapolis College of Art & Design (MCAD) - Teaching Course "Women's Art Institute", 1999 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Photographs - Workshops, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Political Group Actions, undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Scandinavia - International Artists' Studio Program in Sweden (IASPIS), Copenhagen, 2006 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Teaching - General, circa 1980s (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Title Nine Task Force (TNT), 1987-1999 (Box 44, Folder 4, Box Shared Fales 086, Folder 13)
    - "Visiting New York Artist Mary Beth Edelson" Lecture Poster, circa 1970s (Box Shared Fales 086, Folder 14)
    - Washington, D.C. - Smithsonian Seminar, 1974, 2015 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Women, Goddesses, and Friends, 1986 (Box Shared Fales 041, Folder 21)
    - Workshops - Moore College, 1996-1997, 2013 (Box 44, Folder 6, Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series I.E: Reviews, Writings, and Interviews, 1950-2016 (inclusive); 1970-2016 (bulk); 10.35 Linear Feet in 18 manuscript boxes and 5 oversized flat boxes
    Sub-Series I.E contains publications and articles about Mary Beth Edelson's artwork, her role in the feminist art movement, and career as a whole. This sub-series includes both domestic and international press articles. Authors of these pieces include Merlin Stone, Gayle Kimball, Jan Avgikos, and Jack Burnham. In addition to these articles, Sub-Series I.E contains transcripts, correspondence, and notes related to interviews Edelson conducted over the course of her career.
    Books written by Edelson such as Seven Cycles: Public Rituals and Shapeshifters: Seven Mediums, as well as press statements, articles, and poems also written by Edelson can be found in Sub-Series I.E. Similarly, this sub-series contains Edelson's numerous notebooks containing addresses and information for colleagues and exhibition contacts, travel diaries, some research notes, exhibition and artwork ideas, personal notes, and some sketches.
    - A/C Project Room - Statements, undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Alaska - Censorship (Seeing Red, White or Blue), 1992 (Box 111, Folder 1)
    - Arlene Raven - "Crossing Over: Feminism and Art on Social Concern", 1988 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - ArtForum - Articles about Mary Beth Edelson, 1975-1999 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - The Art of Mary Beth Edelson Book, 2002-2003 (Box 44, Folder 10-11)
    - ARTnews - Article about Mary Beth Edelson, 1975-1980 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Artnet - "Book Report" (Walter Robinson), 2002 (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Atlanta Art Papers - "Interview: Mary Beth Edelson", 1980 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Atlanta - Women's Collective, 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Book Mock Up (Xerox Copies), undated (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Books Mary Beth Edelson Published In, 1987-1997 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Books, Papers, Publications, circa 1970s (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Books and Proposals, 1970-2011 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Coming to Power: 25 Years of Sexually X-Plicit Art by Women", 1993, 2016 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Description of Ritual Performances, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Documenting Rituals: What A Modern Day Problem! (Mary Beth Edelson), 1977 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Donald Kuspit - "Art Couples II: Mary Beth Edelson and Robert Stackhouse" (Review), 1983 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Dreams, 1973-1986 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Essays, 1995, 2003, 2009 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Feminist Ritual Round Table - Chain Letter, 1977-1978 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Feminist Studies, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - "Fire - Essay", undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Firsthand: Photographs by Mary Beth Edelson, 1973-1993 and Shooter Series (Book by Jan Avgikos) (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Flash Art, 1975-1982 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Gayle Kimball, 2005 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 46, Folder 7, Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Indianapolis - Press and Reviews about Mary Beth Edelson, 1950-2004 (Box 46, Folder 8-9, Box 114, Folder 11, Box 115, Folder 9)
    - "Inquiry Into Fire" (Press Statement), undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Insights: Self Portraits by Women, 1978 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Interviews, 1977-2015 (Box 46, Folder 12, Box 47, Folder 1-7)
    - Jack Burnham, 1974-1982 (Box 47, Folder 8-9, Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Jan Avgikos - "Mary Beth Edelson: Firsthand, No Reverse Gear" (Review), 1993 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Japanese Review of Mary Beth Edelson, 1986 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Lady Unique: Inclinations of the Night - "Fire Fights Deep Space" (Mary Beth Edelson), 1979 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Landscape & Nature Earth Work, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Mail Art, 1980-1983 (Box 48, Folder 3-4)
    - Making Their Mark: Women Artists Move Into the Mainstream, 1970-85, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Mary Beth Edelson - "An Open Letter to Thomas McEvilley", 1989 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Mary Beth Edelson Text, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Max Kozlof - "Lone Visions, Crowded Frames: Essays on Photography", undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Merlin Stone - Canadian Broadcasting - "Return of the Goddess", 1986-2008 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Merlin Stone - "More Literal Than Michelangelo or Masaccio?", undated (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Mixed Projects -Body Art, Writings, A.I.R., Performance, undated (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Ms. Magazine - Articles about Mary Beth Edelson, 1976-1977 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - New Art Examiner - Articles by Mary Beth Edelson, 1978-1989 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - New Harmony Society Notes, 2006-2007 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - New York Magazine - Review of Mary Beth Edelson, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Notebooks, 1976-2014 (Box 48, Folder 16-18, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51)
    - Notebooks, 1976-2014 (Box 52, Box 53, Box 54)
    - Others Writing About Mary Beth Edelson, 1974-2006 (Box 55, Folder 1-4)
    - Poems, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - The Power of Feminist Art: The American Movement of the 1970s, History and Impact, 1996 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Presentation, Recent Exhibits, Work, & Press, 2015 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Press Paintings - Dolan/Maxwell (Philadelphia & NYC), 1989-1992 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Press - United States, 1971-2016 (Box 56, Folder 1-5, Box 57, Folder 1-7)
    - Press - Vienna, 2003-2004 (Box 58, Folder 2, Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Press - Zurich, 2006-2007 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Reclaiming Paradise: American Women Photograph the Land, 1987-1988 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - "A Review of Seven Cycles: Public Rituals", 1980-1981 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Seven Cycles: Public Rituals (Book by Mary Beth Edelson), 1980 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Shapeshifters: Seven Mediums (Book by Mary Beth Edelson), 1990 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - "Speaking for Myself" (Mary Beth Edelson), 1974-1977, 1997 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Spirituality in Art, undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Spirituality - Letters, Lists of People, 1971-1989 (Box 58, Folder 10-11)
    - Statements - 1970s & 1980s, 1973-1988 (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
    - Strong Hearts Inspired Minds: 22 Interviews with Artists Who Are Mothers, 1996 (Box 59, Folder 3)